hello and welcome to BQ Prime you're
watching earnings with BQ and our guest
today is Mr gopal balachandra the CFO of
icic Lombard General Insurance welcome
to the show sir um sir if we were to
look at the financials closely the the
operating segments motor has done quite
well uh what are your thoughts on the
same you know what's worked this time uh
I think the last quarter was slightly
weak
there yeah so I think let me kind of uh
start with the growth first and then
maybe I can also SP speak in the context
of the underwriting outcome as well for
motor uh so in line with what I had
spoken last time I think I kind of
indicated that directionally or
sequentially we are seeing let's say an
improvement in the overall operating
environment for motor and which is kind
of evident in your quarter two numbers
as well for is Lombard so for example if
you would have seen our growth numbers
for quarter 1 in motor we had a growth
of roughly about 5% that has kind of
increased to almost about 11% for
Quarter Two uh we are still slightly
lower than the market again that's a
conscious call for us to kind of be a
bit guarded at times when the market
continues to exhibit higher levels of
combined ratio so again if you look at
the industry combined ratios for motor
it still continues to operate at an
elevated levels of 120% plus so hence to
that extent while there seems still
seems to be an element of uh competitive
intensity playing out but within that
space I think we are obviously able to
see green shoots and opportunities play
out for us and which is why as I said
directionally the growth for us has been
very very encouraging and to that extent
the gap between us and the industry
growth numbers have significantly got
narrowed down whether you look at it QQ
or whether you look at it month on month
I think we have been able to
significantly bring down the Gap uh at
an overall level uh now when you look at
it from an outcome standpoint uh again
in line with what I had spoken even last
time not specifically in the context of
motor but when you look at it for
overall operating environment of the
companies as a whole uh this year as you
as we all know there has been a change
in the expense of management guidelines
and we do have now let's say the q1
numbers last time when I spoke we did
not have the q1 numbers for every player
in the market uh roughly more than 50%
of the players in the market still
continue to have their expense of
management higher than the stipulated
threshold for S Lombard as we have said
even in the past we have operated well
within the threshold now as as and when
let's say some of these companies will
start to get better on the uh expense of
management numbers it further opens up
the opportunities or doors for us to
write businesses at levels at which we
are comfortable with in so far as the
bottom line is concerned but despite
that I think if you look at it uh the
way the trend line has been progressing
I think we have talked about bringing
down our combin ratios down to 102% for
the company as a whole again not
specifically in the context of motor and
that remains intact I think we are on
course to kind of get to that objective
and even from a loss ratio standpoint
now specifically in the context of motor
again when you would have looked at
numbers on quarter the number looks very
very encouraging though we refrain time
and again to move away from quarterly
numbers to largely look at more yearly
outcomes but directionally again with
the various claims initiatives that we
have taken on the claims front I think
even in the context of motor I think
we've been able to see a positive
underwriting
outcome
so by when do we expect to align with
the industry numbers you said we
slightly below the industry so by the
year end we are aspiring to be at par so
for us again when you look at the lers
that is there for us for growth that's
pretty much very very intact for us
again we are kind of present in all
forms of distribution whether it is
working with the oems or dealership
counters whether it is in the context of
working with the agency distribution or
for the matter of fact to whatever ENT
businesses get Source through motor in
the context of Bank Partners or to that
extent the capabilities that we create
on the digital side I think all the
distribution lers are pretty much in
place we do also have the various
product needs that meets customer
requirements I think the only thing that
we watch for is let's say the
handwriting outcome of the market which
is why I gave that combined Rao number
for the overall industry for motor is
still upwards of 120% Plus at those
levels it honestly does not make uh
sense to grow very aggressive it's very
easy for us to let's say double our
market share in maybe less than six
months but honestly it will come at a
cost of significant underrating uh
adverse changes so that's something that
we have never done uh even historically
and that's something we always tried to
balance growth with profits now which is
where I said as the market starts to get
a lot more easing uh signs getting
reflected then to that extent I think we
will be able to
significantly uh grow in line with the
market or maybe slightly beat the market
Market numbers but as I said
directionally when I look at let's say
quarter 1 industry grew at roughly 21%
in motor we grew as I said 5% quter two
if you look at our growth was about 11%
industry growth was 14% so so clearly we
have been able to see signs of the
extent of gap between us and the
industry growth significantly getting
narrowed down over the next couple of
quarters again as in line with what we
spoke even in the earlier call The
Objective will be to try and see by the
end of the year to grow in line with the
market
so uh now on the health front uh what is
what is ailing the group health segment
which we were in profit last year in the
same quarter and this year there's a
loss so what exactly is happening there
and uh and while on the other side the
private retail health is doing well I
mean the the losses have narrowed but
it's still in a loss so um what more is
expected on the health front so again in
line with what I had spoken even last
time
uh on the health side both the employer
employee or let's say the corporate
Health segments and let's say the retail
SL individual health segment both of
them are preferred segments of
opportunities for us there is enormous
uh levels of under penetration that
exist in either of these segments and
that is where we are very very excited
with the opportunity that the segment
presents uh and if you recollect let me
kind of talk about the retail Health
First now that's a segment we have been
continuing to make investments in
distribution and which kind of takes
time for the distribution to build up
obviously Market also wanted to see a
signs of the distribution getting played
out in terms of the Investments that we'
have been talking about and very happy
to again kind of report even this half
year our growth in the retail Health
numbers have kind of beaten the industry
numbers industry has grown at roughly
whether you take Q2 or whether you take
H1 numbers in both the forms we have
been able to grow faster than the market
so hence to that extent we have actually
seen a small Improvement in market share
for us which is what we are very very
excited with and that's kind of right
playing out both in terms of the top L
objectives that we had set for ourselves
and even in terms of let's say the loss
experience I think we we are very happy
with the range that I had kind of spoken
about even last time we had kind of
talked about the retail Health inity
loss ratio range which we are
comfortable in terms of underwriting
between 65 to 70% and if you see the
loss experience is pretty much kind of
playing out around those levels uh in
terms of outcomes on so hence to that
extent I think the retail Health
opportunity is something that we are
very very excited with and we will
continue to stay invested in building
this franchise even when we look forward
and now coming back to the corporate
Health space uh now again when you which
is why again we keeps I mean you will
continue to hear time and again from me
on this is to kind of refrain from
looking at specifically quarterly
numbers because again what happens in
quarter 2 again not a phenomenon only
for this particular Q2 of this year it's
a phenomenon that you would see across
let's say historical periods as well Q2
typically is a period of monsoons and
whenever there are monsoons you
generally get to see a higher level of
uh Health insurances in terms of claims
because there are a lot more instances
of dangu fever etc etc So to that extent
obviously the loss ratios could stay a
little higher than what you would
normally see for any other quarter but
by the end of the year things get
normalized uh which is why I think when
you kind of look at the overall
corporate Health portfolio even in the
past call which I had kind of indicated
we I had kind of said that we will
largely operate in the range of a loss
which is between 94 95% levels and the
relative cost of acquisition for this
particular line of business is a low
single digit number because we tend to
kind of work directly with the
corporates and to that extent the cost
of acquisition is a very low single
digit number so when I put both both of
this together it kind of again fits
within the overall combined ratio
objective that we have set for ourselves
in writing this segment so hence what
you look at as let's say a slightly
increase in the loss ratios is more I
would say a phenomenon of the nature of
the business in which it kind of
operates with but honestly I think from
our standpoint we are very happy with
the way even this segment if you look at
uh industry has grown roughly at about
24 25% we have grown by almost about 31%
so again we have had an industry beating
number even on the corporate Health
space and the good news is it is a
growth which has been aided by an all
around increase on price we have also
been able to let's say increase volumes
and at the same time we have also been
able to accrate market share so it's
been a combination of all and again the
other good news is we continue to write
more of mid and small corporates where
we are able to get a better price and
equally we have been able to kind of
hold on to that customer for a
relatively longer period of time so
hence honestly the underlying dynamics
of the segment is something which we are
quite happy with and that's something
will continue to be a preferred
segment